# Su Zhang

## Software Engineer

### **CONTACT ME**

**1** 0451 991 558

suzhang79@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/su-zhang-au

https://github.com/coderGirlSu

https://codergirlsu.dev/

Sydney

### **EDUCATION**

### **Computer Science**

**Stanford Online** 

2023

### **Diploma of Information Technology**

Coder Academy

#### **Bachelor of Architecture**

Harbin Institute of Technology 2010 - 2013

### **STRENGTHS**

- Full Stack Web App Development
- Backend Development
- Self Learning
- Problem solving
- AWS fundamental services
- Fluent in Mandarin

### **SKILLS**

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang, Ruby, Python, Node.js, HTML, CSS.
- Frameworks: React, Ruby on Rails ,gRPC, Rest, Jest
- Software: VSCode, Figma, SourceTree, AutoCAD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Buildkite, Backstage, Kubernetes, Git, GitHub, Trello, Heroku, Firebase, Agile Board, Postman, XMind, Balsamiq, draw.io

### **SUMMARY**

I am a full-stack software engineer with one year of experience. As a certified AWS practitioner with a firm grasp of Computer Science, I am passionate about building things and solving problems, especially using generative AI technologies such as LLMs and diffusion models.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Software Engineer Intern**

2022-2023

### **SafetyCulture**

- Developed full-stack team projects in a microservice architecture that involved many different technologies, such as React, Typescript, Golang and Temporal workflow.
- Worked on a project to integrate the <u>Boston Dynamics Spot robot</u> image and temperature data sensors with the SafetyCulture application.

## Robotics Software Engineer SafetyCulture - Boston Dynamics Spot

2023

- Created an innovative solution using the Boston Dynamics Spot robot at SafetyCulture that involved robotics programming to independently navigate a predetermined path, capturing high-quality photos and measuring temperature using infrared sensors.
- Utilised the data collected to conduct comprehensive inspections, integrating with the SafetyCulture platform to provide valuable insights into safety and maintenance requirements, thereby automating tasks that were previously time-consuming, dangerous, and error-prone.
- Leveraged API development skills to upload media to inspection devices used by SafetyCulture customers for more efficient and accurate inspections, enabling seamless access to valuable findings.

## Full Stack Software Engineer

2022

### SafetyCulture - Temporal Workflow Engine

- Implemented Data Governance functionality utilising technologies and tools, including Figma, React, TypeScript, gRPC, Go, and Temporal Workflow.
- Developed an intuitive and user-friendly interface for managing data using Figma, React, and TypeScript.
- Utilised gRPC and Go to create a fast and reliable backend for the feature.
- Integrated Temporal Workflow to efficiently manage complex workflows and ensure the smooth running of the feature.
- Presented the Data Governance feature to a large audience of over 150 engineers within the engineering department.
- Demonstrated exceptional technical expertise and dedication in the successful implementation of the feature.

### **Architect** 2011-2018

### **Harbin University of Science and Technology**

• Drew and designed architectural construction plans and architectural renderings that met client requirements and building regulations using AutoCAD, 3ds Max and SketchUp.

### **AWS Cloud Practitioner Certificate**

**Credentials:** 

https://www.credly.com/badges/4519b7fc-ecbe-419c-8d2c-948bd3cafd34/public\_url

- Successfully obtained the AWS Cloud Practitioner certification in 2023, demonstrating a strong foundation in cloud computing principles and AWS services
- Proficient in core AWS cloud concepts, including cloud architecture, security, and billing, along with a deep understanding of fundamental AWS services and their use cases
- Skilled in managing AWS cloud infrastructure, including virtual servers (EC2), storage (S3), and databases (RDS), ensuring optimal performance and cost-efficiency
- Well-versed in cloud best practices, enabling the design and implementation of scalable, reliable, and secure AWS solutions that meet business objectives and compliance requirements.

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

### OpenAI - Personal writing assistant tool

- Built a personal assistant tool using Golang that leverages AI technology from OpenAI's APIs and integrates into MacOS using Apple shortcuts.
- Features include translating text, enhancing writing, and grammar-checking using the GPT-4 model.
- GitHub: https://github.com/coderGirlSu/translate-tool

### **MERN stack - Chat App**

- Spearheaded the development of a feature-rich MERN stack chat application in collaboration with a team of two.
- Incorporated advanced features such as user authentication, group creation and chat rooms, chat history viewing, adding friends, dark mode, and custom Halloween theme to provide an enhanced user experience.
- Employed Express for advanced backend features and deployed the application on AWS EC2 instances.
- Leveraged Firebase authentication and MongoDB Atlas for efficient database management.
- Utilised React for front-end development and deployed on Netlify for ease of use.
- Ensured the chat software has scalability and provides a solid foundation for future feature development.
- App website: https://tiktalk.codergirlsu.dev/
- GitHub: https://github.com/coderGirlSu/TikTalk-server

### Hackathon - React Emoji Search App

- Built an app to search emojis in a four-person team in one and a half days
- Used ReactJS, JavaScript, CSS and HTML including a YouTube presentation and documentation
- Includes features such as search, click-to-copy emoji, pop-up toast notifications, dark mode and team photos
- Collaboration with team using GitHub fork workflow and PRs
- Deployed on Netlify
- App website: <a href="https://emojis.codergirlsu.dev/">https://emojis.codergirlsu.dev/</a>
- YouTube presentation: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tTJmHlxH-fo">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tTJmHlxH-fo</a>
- **GitHub**: <a href="https://github.com/coderGirlSu/coder-academy-hackathon-team-why-not">https://github.com/coderGirlSu/coder-academy-hackathon-team-why-not</a>

### **React - Fruit Picking Game**

- Built a fruit-picking game using ReactJS, CSS, HTML and JavaScript
- Includes features such as calculating the score, timer, sound effects
- App website: <a href="https://fruit.codergirlsu.dev/">https://fruit.codergirlsu.dev/</a>

### Ruby on Rails - Marketplace

- Created a two-sided marketplace with the following features:
  - File upload capabilities, user authentication, messaging, search, sorting and filtering capabilities
- Developed using Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL, and deployed to Heroku
- **Github:** <a href="https://github.com/coderGirlSu/SuZhang\_T2A2">https://github.com/coderGirlSu/SuZhang\_T2A2</a>

2023